<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SensorLab at Jozef Stefan Institute on SensorLab</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in SensorLab at Jozef Stefan Institute on SensorLab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>SensorLab</copyright><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blaž Bertalanič</title><link>/people/bbertalanic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/people/bbertalanic/</guid><description>Blaž Bertalanič received his Master’s degree in electrical engineering from the Faculty of Electrical engineering, University of Ljubljana. He is currently pursuing his PhD at the same faculty and is working as a researcher at the Department of Communication Systems, Jožef Stefan Institute.</description></item><item><title>Carolina Fortuna</title><link>/people/cfortuna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/people/cfortuna/</guid><description>I am a research fellow working at the Department of Communications Systems at the Jozef Stefan Institute in Ljubljana, Slovenia. I also work with the Data Science team in Bloomberg Media and co-founded Comsensus.
In my research I use technologies from the broad field of artificial intelligence, including machine learning, data mining and symbolic AI to solve problems in wireless and IoT networks. For more details, see my publications on Google Scholar, Research Gate, and my LinkedIn profile.</description></item><item><title>Data science specialists</title><link>/00-data-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/00-data-science/</guid><description>Research group of enthusiast data scientists &amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Embedded devices</title><link>/01-embedded/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/01-embedded/</guid><description>Quickly design and customize responsive mobile-first sites with Bootstrap, the world’s most popular front-end open source toolkit, featuring Sass variables and mixins, responsive grid system, extensive prebuilt components, and powerful JavaScript plugins.</description></item><item><title>Gregor Cerar</title><link>/people/gcerar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/people/gcerar/</guid><description>Gregor Cerar received his Master degree in telecommunications from the Faculty of Electrical Engineering, University of Ljubljana, in 2016. He is currently pursuing the Ph.D. degree with the Jozef Stefan International Postgraduate School. He is also research assistant with the Department of Communication Systems, Jozef Stefan Institute. His main research interests are in IoT, wireless networking of constrained devices, and machine learning applications in IoT.</description></item><item><title>Halil Yetgin</title><link>/people/hyetgin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/people/hyetgin/</guid><description>Halil Yetgin received the B.Eng. degree in computer engineering from Selcuk University, Turkey, in 2008, the M.Sc. degree in wireless communications from the University of Southampton,U.K., in 2010, and the Ph.D. degree in wireless communications with the Next Generation Wireless Research Group under the supervision of Prof. Lajos Hanzo and Dr. Mohammed El-Hajjar, University of Southampton in 2015. He is an Assistant Professor with the Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Bitlis Eren University, Turkey and a research fellow at the Department of Communication Systems of Jožef Stefan Institute, Ljubljana, Slovenia.</description></item><item><title>Mihael "Miha" Mohorčič</title><link>/people/mmohorcic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/people/mmohorcic/</guid><description>Dr. Mihael Mohorcic (DrSc in ElecEng from University of Ljubljana, 2002) is head of the Department of Communication Systems and Scientific Advisor at the Jozef Stefan Institute, and associate professor at the Jozef Stefan International Postgraduate School. His research and working experience include development and performance evaluation of network protocols and architectures for mobile and wireless communication systems, and resource management in terrestrial, stratospheric and satellite networks. His recent research interest is focused on cognitive radio networks, cross-layer protocol design and optimization, “smart” applications of wireless sensor networks, dynamic composition of communication services and wireless experimental testbeds.</description></item><item><title>NRG5</title><link>/projects/nrg5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/nrg5/</guid><description>The NRG-5 project envisages contributing to the 5G PPP/5G Initiative research and development activities and participation at the relevant 5G Working Groups by delivering a novel 5G-PPP compliant, decentralized, &lt;strong>secure&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>resilient&lt;/strong> framework, with &lt;strong>highly availability&lt;/strong> able to homogeneously model and virtualize multi-homed, static or moving, hardware constrained (smart energy) devices, edge computing resources and elastic virtualized services over electricity and gas infrastructure assets combined with the telecommunications infrastructure covering the full spectrum of the communication and computational needs.</description></item><item><title>Research &amp; Development</title><link>/03-localization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/03-localization/</guid><description>Quickly design and customize responsive mobile-first sites with Bootstrap, the world’s most popular front-end open source toolkit, featuring Sass variables and mixins, responsive grid system, extensive prebuilt components, and powerful JavaScript plugins.</description></item><item><title>SAAM: Supporting Active Ageing Through Multimodal Coaching</title><link>/projects/saam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/saam/</guid><description>The project aims to develop and validate a Virtual Assistant-Coach that supports the process of healthy ageing by preserving physical, cognitive, mental, and social well-being of older citizens, and prolonging the period of life they can live safely at home. SAAM focuses on innovative, unobtrusive technology-enabled approaches, with a novel and practical emphasis on wearable and ambient sensing.</description></item><item><title>Sensor Networks</title><link>/02-sensor-networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/02-sensor-networks/</guid><description>Quickly design and customize responsive mobile-first sites with Bootstrap, the world’s most popular front-end open source toolkit, featuring Sass variables and mixins, responsive grid system, extensive prebuilt components, and powerful JavaScript plugins.</description></item></channel></rss>