<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opportunities on SensorLab — Jozef Stefan Institute</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/</link><description>Recent content in Opportunities on SensorLab — Jozef Stefan Institute</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>SensorLab</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Early-stage researcher to work on an applied project</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/2023-phd-position/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/2023-phd-position/</guid><description>SensorLab, in collaboration with ComSensus is looking for a early-stage researcher to work in the area of smart infrastructure management using artificial intelligence, with a focus on algorithms in the field of Deep Reinforcement Learning. The position will offer a unique academia-industry set-up in which the candidate will work both at the &amp;ldquo;Jožef Stefan&amp;rdquo; Institute, where SensorLab is located, and at the ComSensus office in Ljubljana. ComSensus is a young tech company where the candidate will design and conduct experiments, perform data analysis, and deploy developed deep learning models on experimental setups.</description></item><item><title>For undergraduate and master students</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/students/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/students/</guid><description>Do you want to build up your career by doing research during your undergrad studies? Are you interested in smart infrastructures and artificial intelligence?
We offer Work on real projects with European partners and industry. Learn from a world class team of researchers. Build knowledge and experience that will catapult your carrer. Additional training through summer schools, international conferences, etc. Flexible working time with focus on results. We are looking for highly motivated and pro-active collaborators.</description></item></channel></rss>