<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opportunities on SensorLab — Jozef Stefan Institute</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/</link><description>Recent content in Opportunities on SensorLab — Jozef Stefan Institute</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>SensorLab</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PhD Student in Intelligent Orchestration</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/2024-phd-ai-planning-6g/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/2024-phd-ai-planning-6g/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
 &lt;strong>Deadline:&lt;/strong> Till the position is filled.
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>&lt;strong>Description:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Formulate a device and input agnostic fluid communication and computation scenario where humans can architect
and instantiate their home digital space with personalized software digital assistants (i.e. customized GPTs or Personas) and inputs
(i.e. home speaker systems, touch pads, readable holographic projections etc). 2) Extract the network and computation orchestration
challenges for supporting such scenario 3) Analyse the SoA of theoretical advancements of neuro-symbolic AI 5) Develop the
theoretical framework to enable zero-touch orchestration of the personalized digital space by proposing a neuro-symbolic formalism
to address the challenges. The applicant&amp;rsquo;s tasks will be:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Conducting world-class, original scientific research.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Writing scientific papers for high impact journals and conferences.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regularly complete all coursework as outlined in the PhD program of study.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contributing to project activities, including research and scientific dissemination.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Required qualifications and selection criteria:&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
The applicant must hold a MSc degree or equivalent in related field (computer science, electrical engineering, physics, or mathematics). For this position, it is required to have analytic thinking, good knowledge of at least one programming or scripting language (Python, Matlab, Javascript, C++, etc.) and a good command of English language. Any prior experience with data analytics, code development, communication networks or/and embedded systems is a plus.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Early-stage researcher to work on an applied project</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/2023-phd-position/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/2023-phd-position/</guid><description>&lt;p>SensorLab, in collaboration with &lt;a href="https://comsensus.eu">ComSensus&lt;/a> is looking for a early-stage researcher to work in the area of smart infrastructure management using artificial intelligence, with a focus on algorithms in the field of Deep Reinforcement Learning. The position will offer a unique academia-industry set-up in which the candidate will work both at the &lt;a href="https://ijs.si">&amp;ldquo;Jožef Stefan&amp;rdquo; Institute&lt;/a>, where SensorLab is located, and at the ComSensus office in Ljubljana. ComSensus is a young tech company where the candidate will design and conduct experiments, perform data analysis, and deploy developed deep learning models on experimental setups. The resulting mixed set-up will enable the candidate to gain an in-depth understanding of mobile telecommunication systems, energy systems, smart grids, and state-of-the-art techniques for managing radio and network resources in wireless networks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For undergraduate and master students</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/students/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/opportunities/students/</guid><description>&lt;p>Do you want to build up &lt;strong>your career&lt;/strong> by doing research during your undergrad studies? Are you interested in &lt;strong>smart infrastructures&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>artificial intelligence&lt;/strong>?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="we-offer">We offer&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Work on &lt;strong>real projects&lt;/strong> with &lt;strong>European partners&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>industry&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Learn from a &lt;strong>world class team&lt;/strong> of researchers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Build knowledge and experience that will catapult your carrer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Additional training through summer schools, international conferences, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flexible working time with focus on results.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="we-are-looking-for">We are looking for&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>highly motivated and pro-active collaborators.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Are you interested? Introduce yourself to &lt;a href="mailto:sensorlab@ijs.si">sensorlab@ijs.si&lt;/a> by sending:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>