<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>People on SensorLab — Jozef Stefan Institute</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/</link><description>Recent content in People on SensorLab — Jozef Stefan Institute</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>SensorLab</copyright><atom:link href="https://sensorlab.github.io/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adnan Bekan</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/abekan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/abekan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ahmad Anaqreh</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/aanaqreh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/aanaqreh/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ahmad Anaqreh received a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science in 2019 and a Ph.D. in Computer Science in 2024 from the University of Szeged, Hungary. His research focuses on optimizing graph theory problems, particularly NP-hard problems&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alexandra Moraru</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/amoraru/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/amoraru/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Andrej Čampa</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/acampa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/acampa/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blaž Bertalanič</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/bbertalanic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/bbertalanic/</guid><description>&lt;p>Blaž Bertalanič received his Master’s degree in electrical engineering from the Faculty of Electrical Engineering, University of Ljubljana. He completed his PhD at the same faculty in 2024 and is now a postdoctoral researcher at the Department of Communication Systems, Jožef Stefan Institute.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Carolina Fortuna</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/cfortuna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/cfortuna/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am a research fellow working at the Department of Communications Systems at the Jozef Stefan Institute in Ljubljana, Slovenia. I also work with the Data Science team in Bloomberg Media and co-founded Comsensus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my research I use technologies from the broad field of artificial intelligence, including machine learning, data mining and symbolic AI to solve problems in wireless and IoT networks. For more details, see my publications on Google Scholar, Research Gate, and my LinkedIn profile.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Denis Sodin</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/dsodin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/dsodin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Din Mušić</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/dmusic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/dmusic/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gregor Cerar</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/gcerar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/gcerar/</guid><description>&lt;p>Gregor Cerar earned his Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree (2013) and Master&amp;rsquo;s degree (2016) from the &lt;a href="https://www.fe.uni-lj.si/en/">Faculty of Electrical Engineering&lt;/a> at the University of Ljubljana, where he completed the Telecommunications study program. He obtained his Ph.D. in Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) in 2021 from the &lt;a href="https://www.mps.si/en/">International Postgraduate School of Jožef Stefan&lt;/a>, in collaboration with the &lt;a href="https://e6.ijs.si/">Department of Communication Systems&lt;/a> at the Jožef Stefan Institute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently, he holds a part-time postdoctoral position with the &lt;a href="https://e6.ijs.si/">Department of Communication Systems&lt;/a> at the &lt;a href="http://ijs.si">Jožef Stefan Institute&lt;/a> and works as a research engineer at &lt;a href="https://www.comsensus.eu/">ComSensus&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Halil Yetgin</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/hyetgin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/hyetgin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Halil Yetgin received the B.Eng. degree in computer engineering from Selcuk University, Turkey, in 2008, the M.Sc. degree in wireless communications from the University of Southampton,U.K., in 2010, and the Ph.D. degree in wireless communications with the Next Generation Wireless Research Group under the supervision of Prof. Lajos Hanzo and Dr. Mohammed El-Hajjar, University of Southampton in 2015. He is an Assistant Professor with the Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Bitlis Eren University, Turkey and a research fellow at the Department of Communication Systems of Jožef Stefan Institute, Ljubljana, Slovenia. His research interests include the development of intelligent communication systems, energy-efficient cross-layer design, resource allocation of the future wireless communication networks, UAV communication networks and underwater sensor networks. He was a recipient of the full scholarship granted by the Republic of Turkey, Ministry of National Education.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ivan Boskov</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/iboskov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/iboskov/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jernej Hribar</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/jhribar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/jhribar/</guid><description>&lt;p>Jernej Hribar is a &lt;a href="https://marie-sklodowska-curie-actions.ec.europa.eu/actions/postdoctoral-fellowships">Marie Skłodowska-Curie Action Fellow&lt;/a> in the &lt;a href="https://e6.ijs.si/">Department of Communication Systems&lt;/a> since October 2022. His MSCA action - TimeSmart - investigates the applicability of the novel Age of Information metric in smart grids. From 2019-2022, he was a postdoctoral researcher in the &lt;a href="https://connectcentre.ie/">CONNECT Centre&lt;/a> for Future Networks and Communications at &lt;a href="https://www.tcd.ie/">Trinity College Dublin, Ireland&lt;/a>. He was involved in an international collaborative project between Trinity College Dublin and &lt;a href="https://www.tsinghua.edu.cn/en/">Tsinghua University&lt;/a> using machine learning techniques to assist future networks with decision-making problems in smart cities. He received an undergraduate degree in electrical engineering from the &lt;a href="https://www.uni-lj.si/eng/">University of Ljubljana&lt;/a>, Slovenia, in 2014 and a Ph.D. from Trinity College Dublin, Ireland, in 2020. His PhD focused on improving the sustainability of large-scale sensor deployments using reinforcement learning and leveraging the freshness of correlated information measured by the Age of Information metric.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jošt Novljan</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/jnovljan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/jnovljan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Klemen Bregar</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/kbregar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/kbregar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ljupcho Milosheski</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/lmilosheski/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/lmilosheski/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Maria Porcius</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mporcius/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mporcius/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Marko Hudomalj</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mhudomalj/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mhudomalj/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Marko Mihelin</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mmihelin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mmihelin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Matevž Vučnik</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mvucnik/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mvucnik/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Miha Smolnikar</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/msmolnikar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/msmolnikar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mihael "Miha" Mohorčič</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mmohorcic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mmohorcic/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dr. Mihael Mohorcic (DrSc in ElecEng from University of Ljubljana, 2002) is head of the Department of Communication Systems and Scientific Advisor at the Jozef Stefan Institute, and associate professor at the Jozef Stefan International Postgraduate School. His research and working experience include development and performance evaluation of network protocols and architectures for mobile and wireless communication systems, and resource management in terrestrial, stratospheric and satellite networks. His recent research interest is focused on cognitive radio networks, cross-layer protocol design and optimization, “smart” applications of wireless sensor networks, dynamic composition of communication services and wireless experimental testbeds. He participated in several COST actions and FP projects considering terrestrial &amp;amp; satellite mobile communications, stratospheric telecommunication systems and wireless sensor networks, as well as in basic and applied national projects. Currently he is involved in three ongoing FP7 projects (CITI-SENSE, Fed4FIRE, SUNSEED) and one H2020 project (eWINE); and he leads a national applied research project on advanced ray-tracing techniques in radio environment characterization and radio localization (L2-7664). He is author or co-author of more than 140 refereed journal and conference papers, co-author of two books published by John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons, contributor to 9 book chapters (5 published by Springer) and co-author of one US patent. He regularly serves as Technical Program Committee member to various international conferences and workshops, is a member of editorial board of the Electrotechnical Review (ISSN: 0013-5852) and of the International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks (ISSN: 1550-1329), and was a guest editor to the Special issue on research methodologies for performance evaluation of wireless network solutions in EURASIP Journal on Wireless Communications and Networking (ISSN 1687-1472). He is Senior Member of IEEE (VTS and ComSoc).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mikhail Krasnov</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mkrasnov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mkrasnov/</guid><description>&lt;p>I received my bachelor deegre in physics at Moscow Institute and Physics and Thechologies in 2023, after which I was working as Data Scientist at Yandex till 2024. Me research interests include self-supervised learning, time series analysis and deep clustering.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sadig Gojayev</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/sgodjayev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/sgodjayev/</guid><description>&lt;p>I received my Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Data Science from Eötvös Loránd University, Budapest in 2024. My research is about AI planning methods and I am currently pursuing PhD in Jozef Stefan International Postgraduate School.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shih-Kai Chou</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/skchou/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/skchou/</guid><description>&lt;p>I received my Master’s degree in communication engineering from &lt;a href="https://www.ccu.edu.tw/?Lang=en">National Chung Cheng University&lt;/a> (CCU), Taiwan in 2014 and a Ph.D. from &lt;a href="https://www.qub.ac.uk/">Queen’s University&lt;/a>, Belfast, U.K. in 2023. My Ph.D. focused on Reconfigurable Intelligent Surface (RIS/IRS), more specifically, the real-world setup and optimization of RIS-aided wireless systems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Timotej Gale</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/tgale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/tgale/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tomaž Šolc</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/tsolc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/tsolc/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Zoltan Padrah</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/zpadrah/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/zpadrah/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>