<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>People on SensorLab — Jozef Stefan Institute</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/</link><description>Recent content in People on SensorLab — Jozef Stefan Institute</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>SensorLab</copyright><atom:link href="https://sensorlab.github.io/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Andrej Čampa</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/acampa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/acampa/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Anže Pirnat</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/apirnat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/apirnat/</guid><description>Anže Pirnat is currently pursuing a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in electrical engineering and working as a research intern in the Department of Communication Systems at Jože Stefan Institute.</description></item><item><title>Blaž Bertalanič</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/bbertalanic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/bbertalanic/</guid><description>Blaž Bertalanič received his Master’s degree in electrical engineering from the Faculty of Electrical engineering, University of Ljubljana. He is currently pursuing his PhD at the same faculty and is working as a researcher at the Department of Communication Systems, Jožef Stefan Institute.</description></item><item><title>Carolina Fortuna</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/cfortuna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/cfortuna/</guid><description>I am a research fellow working at the Department of Communications Systems at the Jozef Stefan Institute in Ljubljana, Slovenia. I also work with the Data Science team in Bloomberg Media and co-founded Comsensus.
In my research I use technologies from the broad field of artificial intelligence, including machine learning, data mining and symbolic AI to solve problems in wireless and IoT networks. For more details, see my publications on Google Scholar, Research Gate, and my LinkedIn profile.</description></item><item><title>Denis Sodin</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/dsodin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/dsodin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Din Mušić</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/dmusic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/dmusic/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gregor Cerar</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/gcerar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/gcerar/</guid><description>Gregor Cerar received his Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s (2013) and Master&amp;rsquo;s (2016) degrees from the Faculty of Electrical Engineering of the University of Ljubljana, where he completed the Telecommunications study programme, and the Ph.D. degree (2021) from International Postgraduate School of Jožef Stefan in Information and Communication technologies with the Department of Communication Systems, Jožef Stefan Institute. He is currently a research associate with the Department of Communication Systems, Jožef Stefan Institute.</description></item><item><title>Halil Yetgin</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/hyetgin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/hyetgin/</guid><description>Halil Yetgin received the B.Eng. degree in computer engineering from Selcuk University, Turkey, in 2008, the M.Sc. degree in wireless communications from the University of Southampton,U.K., in 2010, and the Ph.D. degree in wireless communications with the Next Generation Wireless Research Group under the supervision of Prof. Lajos Hanzo and Dr. Mohammed El-Hajjar, University of Southampton in 2015. He is an Assistant Professor with the Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Bitlis Eren University, Turkey and a research fellow at the Department of Communication Systems of Jožef Stefan Institute, Ljubljana, Slovenia.</description></item><item><title>Klemen Bregar</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/kbregar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/kbregar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ljupcho Milosheski</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/lmilosheski/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/lmilosheski/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Marko Hudomalj</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mhudomalj/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mhudomalj/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Marko Mihelin</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mmihelin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mmihelin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Matevž Vučnik</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mvucnik/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mvucnik/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Miha Smolnikar</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/msmolnikar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/msmolnikar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mihael "Miha" Mohorčič</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mmohorcic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/people/mmohorcic/</guid><description>Dr. Mihael Mohorcic (DrSc in ElecEng from University of Ljubljana, 2002) is head of the Department of Communication Systems and Scientific Advisor at the Jozef Stefan Institute, and associate professor at the Jozef Stefan International Postgraduate School. His research and working experience include development and performance evaluation of network protocols and architectures for mobile and wireless communication systems, and resource management in terrestrial, stratospheric and satellite networks. His recent research interest is focused on cognitive radio networks, cross-layer protocol design and optimization, “smart” applications of wireless sensor networks, dynamic composition of communication services and wireless experimental testbeds.</description></item></channel></rss>