<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>artificial intelligence on SensorLab — Jozef Stefan Institute</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/tags/artificial-intelligence/</link><description>Recent content in artificial intelligence on SensorLab — Jozef Stefan Institute</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>SensorLab</copyright><atom:link href="https://sensorlab.github.io/tags/artificial-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AI-ASSIST: Artificial intelligence based real-time power system stability assessment</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/ai-assist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/ai-assist/</guid><description>The AI-ASSIST project focuses on developing a real-time dynamic stability assessment (DSA) tool for electric power systems, using artificial intelligence to enhance stability monitoring in response to rapidly changing environmental and technological demands. The project aims to integrate advanced monitoring infrastructure with AI techniques to predict and address potential instabilities in power systems. Organizations involved in this initiative include the University of Ljubljana&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Electrical Engineering (UL-FE), the Jožef Stefan Institute (JSI), and ELES, Slovenia’s national transmission system operator.</description></item><item><title>NANCY: An Artificial Intelligent Aided Unified Network for Secure Beyond 5G Long Term Evolution</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/nancy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/nancy/</guid><description>The overall aim of NANCY is to introduce a secure and intelligent architecture for the beyond the fifth generation (B5G) wireless network. Leveraging AI and blockchain, NANCY enables secure and intelligent resource management, flexible networking, and orchestration. In this direction, novel architectures, namely point-to-point (P2P) connectivity for device-to-device connectivity, mesh networking, and relay-based communications, as well as protocols for medium access, mobility management, and resource allocation will be designed.
These architectures and protocols will make the most by jointly optimizing the midhaul, and fronthaul. This is expected to enable truly distributed intelligence and transform the network to a low-power computer. Likewise, by following a holistic optimization approach and leveraging the developments in blockchain, NANCY aims at supporting E2E personalized, multi-tenant and perpetual protection.</description></item></channel></rss>