<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>spectrum on SensorLab</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/tags/spectrum/</link><description>Recent content in spectrum on SensorLab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>SensorLab</copyright><atom:link href="https://sensorlab.github.io/tags/spectrum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CREW</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/crew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/crew/</guid><description>The main target of the Cognitive Radio Experimentation World – CREW project is to establish an open federated test platform, which facilitates experimentally-driven research on advanced spectrum sensing, cognitive radio and cognitive networking strategies in view of horizontal and vertical spectrum sharing in licensed and unlicensed bands.</description></item><item><title>eWINE</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/ewine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/ewine/</guid><description>The elastic Wireless Networking Experimentation (eWINE) is a research project funded by the European Comission under the Horizon2020 programme (Call: H2020-ICT-2015. Topic: ICT-12-2015). The main goal of eWINE is to realize elastic networks that can scale to a high number of users in a short timespan through the use of an agile infrastructure (intelligent software and flexible hardware), enabling: 1) dynamic on-demand end-to-end wireless connectivity service provisioning, 2) elastic resource sharing in dense heterogeneous and small cell networks (HetSNets), 3) intelligent and informed configuration of the physical layer.</description></item><item><title>FED4FIRE+</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/fed4fire/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/fed4fire/</guid><description>Fed4FIRE+ is an Integrating Project under the European Union’s Programme Horizon 2020, addressing the work programme topic Future Internet Research and Experimentation. It started in January 2017 and will run for 60 months, until the end of September 2021. The Fed4FIRE+ project is the successor of the Fed4FIRE project.</description></item></channel></rss>