<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Energy on SensorLab — Jozef Stefan Institute</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/tags/energy/</link><description>Recent content in Energy on SensorLab — Jozef Stefan Institute</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>SensorLab</copyright><atom:link href="https://sensorlab.github.io/tags/energy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AI-ASSIST: Artificial intelligence based real-time power system stability assessment</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/ai-assist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/ai-assist/</guid><description>The AI-ASSIST project focuses on developing a real-time dynamic stability assessment (DSA) tool for electric power systems, using artificial intelligence to enhance stability monitoring in response to rapidly changing environmental and technological demands. The project aims to integrate advanced monitoring infrastructure with AI techniques to predict and address potential instabilities in power systems. Organizations involved in this initiative include the University of Ljubljana&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Electrical Engineering (UL-FE), the Jožef Stefan Institute (JSI), and ELES, Slovenias national transmission system operator. The Jožef Stefan Institute is responsible for developing and optimizing AI techniques for database management and real-time recognition of power system conditions.</description></item><item><title>BD4OPEM</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/bd4opem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/bd4opem/</guid><description>Energy power systems face big challenges to cope with grid integration demands of an ever-increasing number of distributed generation and consumption devices in an interconnected world. Technology offers a huge range of opportunities to develop solutions in the uncertain current and upcoming Energy market situation. This proposal considers Open Innovation as a natural solution to create a seamless link and balance between energy stakeholders needs and the solutions to be developed.</description></item><item><title>DEFENDER</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/defender/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/defender/</guid><description>Defending the European Energy Infrastructures is a research project funded by is a research project funded by the European Comission under the Horizon2020 programme (Call: CIP-2016-2017-1. Topic: CIP-01-2016-2017). Critical Energy infrastructures (CEI) protection and security are becoming of utmost importance in our everyday life. However, cyber and system-theoretic approaches fail to provide appropriate security levels to CEIs, since they are often used in isolation and build on incomplete attack models, resulting in silos-like security management fragmented operational policies. To face these challenges, DEFENDER will (i) model CEIs as distributed Cyber-Physical Systems for managing the potential reciprocal effects of cyber and physical threats (ii) deploy a novel security governance model, which leverages on lifecycle assessment for cost-effective security management over the time (iii) bring people at centre stage by empowering them as virtual sensors for threat detection, as first level emergency responders to attacks, or by considering workforce as potential threats. DEFENDER will adapt, integrate, upscale and validate a number of TRL 4-5 technologies and deploy them within a TRL7 integrated yet adaptable framework for CEI security, resilience and self-healing “by design”, with a view to address, detect, and mitigate cyber-physical threats.</description></item><item><title>EnerTEF: Common European-scale Energy Artificial Intelligence Federated Testing and Experimentation Facility</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/enertef/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/enertef/</guid><description>&lt;p>EnerTEF responds to the soaring demand for reliable AI products in the evolving energy sector. It pioneers a Common Federated AI Testing and Experimentation Facility to bridge the gap between demand and limited availability of rigorously tested AI products. Aligned with European Commission initiatives, EnerTEF leverages foundational projects like the Common European Energy Data Space and AIoD. Through specialized &amp;lsquo;AI Living Labs,&amp;rsquo; EnerTEF fosters collaboration between energy stakeholders and AI developers to create adaptive models that align with evolving energy systems. &amp;lsquo;Bridging Centralized Access&amp;rsquo; ensures data privacy and security in federated testing, adhering to EU regulations and addressing ethical concerns. &amp;lsquo;Seamless Federated Integration&amp;rsquo; tackles integrating AI technologies across domains, enhancing cross-sector collaboration. &amp;lsquo;Long-term Sustainability and Go-to-Market Strategy&amp;rsquo; focuses on bringing AI innovations to market. In a nutshell, EnerTEF&amp;rsquo;s primary goal is to establish a Common European-scale Energy AI Federated TEF, facilitating extensive adaptation, validation, and upscale of AI tools and services across the energy sector. The project&amp;rsquo;s network of five primary nodes, complemented by three satellites, ensures a comprehensive approach to testing AI-based technologies in real-world operational environments. This setup contributes to the market uptake of trustworthy AI, ensuring their readiness, accessibility, and applicability to real-world scenarios.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EuConNeCts3</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/euconnects3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/euconnects3/</guid><description>It is the purpose of EuConNeCts3, a Supporting Action, to organise the following 2 editions, 2018 and 2019, of the EC sponsored conference in the area of communication networks and systems (EuCNC – European Conference on Networks and Communications), continuing the successful organisation of this conference since 2014. EuCNC will continue to serve as a technical and scientific conference for researchers, namely European ones, to show their work in the area of Telecommunications, focusing on communication networks and systems, and also reaching services and applications. The conference will not be restricted to European researchers, rather aiming at attracting others from all the other regions in the world. It will also serve as a showcase for the work developed by projects co-financed by the EC, namely those arising from H2020 calls, and more specifically, those addressing 5G and beyond. Nonetheless, it also aims at attracting works in the area of communication networks and systems from other objectives.</description></item><item><title>GOTOTWIN: Advancing Renewable Energy in the Adriatic Ionian Region through the Use of Digital Twins</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/gototwin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/gototwin/</guid><description>The GoToTwin project addresses the common challenge of accelerating the adoption and integration of renewable energy sources in the Adriatic Ionian region. The project leverages digital twin technology to tackle pressing energy and sustainability issues in the region.</description></item><item><title>NOO TimeSmart: Timeliness of Information in Smart Grids Networks</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/noo-timesmart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/noo-timesmart/</guid><description>The MSCA PF TimeSmart project continues under additional ARIS funding through the NOO initiative, supporting the reintegration and further international engagement of Slovenian researchers. The work of NOO TimeSmart focuses on advancing the practical deployment, robustness, and scalability of the methods developed in the MSCA TimeSmart fellowship. The project strengthens cloud-enabled processing of timely information, integrates AoI-aware forecasting and intelligent energy management into operational frameworks, and evaluates their performance in larger, more diverse smart-grid settings. By deepening the role of the Age of Information in real-time decision-making and coordination across distributed energy assets, the project moves the TimeSmart concepts closer to real-world readiness.</description></item><item><title>NRG5</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/nrg5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/nrg5/</guid><description>The NRG-5 project envisages contributing to the 5G PPP/5G Initiative research and development activities and participation at the relevant 5G Working Groups by delivering a novel 5G-PPP compliant, decentralized, &lt;strong>secure&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>resilient&lt;/strong> framework, with &lt;strong>highly availability&lt;/strong> able to homogeneously model and virtualize multi-homed, static or moving, hardware constrained (smart energy) devices, edge computing resources and elastic virtualized services over electricity and gas infrastructure assets combined with the telecommunications infrastructure covering the full spectrum of the communication and computational needs.</description></item><item><title>TimeSmart: Timeliness of Information in Smart Grids Networks</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/timesmart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/timesmart/</guid><description>TimeSmart project will investigate the applicability of the novel Age of Information metric in smart grid networks. While the metric has become a valuable tool for measuring the system&amp;rsquo;s performance, its practical value and impact in the real-time system are left unanswered. This project seeks to remedy that by applying the metric to a system in which the timing of collected data, currently measured through jitter or latency, profoundly impacts management and control. The AoI offers a new perspective on how the system should collect and process information, as such decisions are also based on the context of processed information(their semantic nature). In turn, the new approach can offer an innovative way of improving the efficiency of renewable electrical energy supply and electrical loads by taking advantage of the available edge infrastructure. This project aims to adopt the AoI metric in smart grid networks to improve the energy transmission efficiency, achievable through more timely collected information, to save energy.</description></item><item><title>TIMIN6: Timely and Sustainable Information Management in 6G Networks</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/timin6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/timin6/</guid><description>The main goal of the TIMIN6 project is to design a new data collection method based on the Age of Information (AoI) metric in connection with aspects of sustainable resource management. AoI is a relatively new and not yet fully understood metric in the field of information science. Considering the AoI can significantly impact energy consumption in data collection, but many aspects and the actual applicability of the metric still need to be explored. While most research in this area focuses on finding more efficient ways to extract information from already collected data, the TIMIN6 project will focus on the question of how frequently devices should collect and transmit data to operate in a more sustainable manner. The goal of this approach is to reduce unnecessarily wasted energy in the billions of devices that will make up 6G networks, enabling a more sustainable future. The project is funded by Slovenian Research and Innovation Agency (ARIS).</description></item></channel></rss>