<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>testbed on SensorLab</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/tags/testbed/</link><description>Recent content in testbed on SensorLab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>SensorLab</copyright><atom:link href="https://sensorlab.github.io/tags/testbed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CREW</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/crew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/crew/</guid><description>The main target of the Cognitive Radio Experimentation World – CREW project is to establish an open federated test platform, which facilitates experimentally-driven research on advanced spectrum sensing, cognitive radio and cognitive networking strategies in view of horizontal and vertical spectrum sharing in licensed and unlicensed bands.</description></item><item><title>FED4FIRE+</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/fed4fire/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/fed4fire/</guid><description>Fed4FIRE+ is an Integrating Project under the European Union’s Programme Horizon 2020, addressing the work programme topic Future Internet Research and Experimentation. It started in January 2017 and will run for 60 months, until the end of September 2021. The Fed4FIRE+ project is the successor of the Fed4FIRE project.</description></item><item><title>WISHFUL</title><link>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/wishful/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sensorlab.github.io/projects/wishful/</guid><description>The WiSHFUL project (Wireless Software and Hardware platforms for Flexible and Unified radio and network controL) will reduce the threshold for experimentation in view of wireless innovation creation and by increasing the realism of experimentation. The WiSHFUL project is funded by the European Commission’s Horizon 2020 Programme under grant agreement n645274. The project started on January 1st 2015 and will last for 36 months.
Our role: Open call extension of the WiSHFUL project with addition of LOG-a-TEC testbed 5G capillary capabilities and adaptation of WiSHFUL universal programming interfaces for the use in the LOG-a-TEC testbed.</description></item></channel></rss>